<resources>
    <string name="app_name">EPMC</string>
    <string name="tv41">At East Parade, you will find people from all the six dioceses of CSI in Kerala, some who were born and brought up in Bangalore while some others have just moved in.</string>
    <string name="tv24">East Parade is a diaspora church whose members migrated to Bangalore from Kerala over the last couple of generations.</string>
    <string name="tv37">The services are conducted in Malayalam, with an English service once a month.</string>
    <string name="tv42">When you come to East Parade on a weekend our aim is that you would be inspired by the sermon, encouraged by the worship, welcomed by our amazing community of people and be reminded that God’s grace is here!</string>
    <string name="tv84">Our goal at East Parade is to create environments and experiences where you can encounter God in the midst of your life.</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="tv123">The choir meets for practice every Sunday after the worship service. Vocal training involves rigorous breathing and tonal lessons and exercises. It is the synergy of this training and blessing from above that equips the singers and fine tune their voices to render pieces that an ordinary choir would not normally attempt. The East Parade Chorale has, to its credit, a handful of Concerts in addition to Christmas Carol Services which is an annual event.</string>
    <string name="tv124">You don’t need to be a great singer to join the choir at East Parade. God takes a bunch of voices—some strong and some not as strong—and blends them together to create beautiful music that honors Him.</string>
    <string name="tv88">We welcome anyone who has a wish to sing for the lord to join us.</string>
    <string name="tv90">Please contact anyone from the choir group, and they would be happy to help you out.</string>
    <string name="b26">Goals</string>
    <string name="tv134">b) To help children develop good singing and musicianship skills to foster the enjoyment of singing.</string>
    <string name="tv135">a) To teach children the core of hymns and spiritual songs, which help them to learn the music of the faith and begin to trust, that God’s promises are theirs.</string>
    <string name="tv133">One intangible but substantial benefit we reap from the junior Choir is that the children learn that they are part of the worship services and that realization is likely to remain with them through out their life.</string>
    <string name="tv26">Rev. Nebu Skariah (Presbyter-In-Charge)</string>
    <string name="tv137">Rt. Rev. Dharmaraj Rasalam (CSI Moderator)</string>
    <string name="tv27">Rev. Dr. Prasana Kumar Samuel (Bishop of KCD)</string>
    <string name="tv141">Rev. Dn. Darwin V. Vadakkethalakkal
        (Asst. Presbyter-In-Charge)</string>
    <string name="tv43">+91 9901801555</string>
    <string name="tv81">+91 8971357074</string>
    <string name="tv38">Rev. Dn. Darwin V Vadakkethalakkal</string>
    <string name="tv40">Rev. Nebu Skariah</string>
    <string name="tv4">8025582867</string>
    <string name="tv12">Church Office</string>
    <string name="tv11">Assistant-Presbyter</string>
    <string name="tv8">Presbyter-In-Charge</string>
    <string name="b10">Choir</string>
    <string name="b18">Mission and Ministry</string>
    <string name="b20">Senior Christian Fellowship</string>
    <string name="b19">Women\'s Fellowship</string>
    <string name="b17">Youth Fellowship</string>
    <string name="b15">Sunday School</string>
    <string name="tv120">Mission Convention</string>
    <string name="tv119">Back to School Project</string>
    <string name="tv118">Christmas gifts</string>
    <string name="tv16">The Cross continuous to be the sign of hope for the witnessing Church, which strives towards Unity, Peace and Reconciliation as a vibrant Channel of God.</string>
    <string name="tv114">The Church through her mission expresses solidarity with the broken communities for a new hope to face the challenges of life.</string>
    <string name="tv113">The Church of South India affirms that the Church is the Servant of God to carry on the mission rooted in Jesus Christ.</string>
    <string name="tv115">“That they all may be one, and that the world may believe that you have sent me”</string>
    <string name="tv117">And the Church of South India would become an effective instrument of God’s mission so there will be Greater peace Closer fellowship Fuller life in the Church Renewed commitment for the proclamation of the Gospel of Jesus Christ through word and deed.</string>
    <string name="tv116">The Church of South India (CSI) affirms that the purpose of the union is to fulfill the priestly prayer of Jesus Christ, the Lord of the Church</string>
    <string name="tv55">Based on the Scriptures.</string>
    <string name="tv13">Mission</string>
    <string name="tv71">Vision</string>
    <string name="tv29">The Malayalam Holy Communion service starts at 6:30am every Sunday and at 10:15am on all Sundays except the third.</string>
    <string name="tv35">Enter from either the MG Road entrance or the Dickenson Road entrance to the Church Campus. Our parking volunteers will escort you to the closest available parking spot.</string>
    <string name="tv33">You can find our location on the map.</string>
    <string name="tv31">Where should I park?</string>
    <string name="tv34">When does the service start?</string>
    <string name="tv32">How do I get there?</string>
    <string name="b32">Visit Us</string>
    <string name="tv91">The membership is open to all senior members of the church who have retired from their normal work.</string>
    <string name="tv93">When SCF started, there were only 34 members, which have now grown to over 200 in 20 year’s time.</string>
    <string name="tv92">The members find time to be with the bereaved families in prayer and also spend time with families going through difficult times.</string>
    <string name="tv73">The Senior Christian Fellowship (SCF) formed in December 1997 is the newest organ of the East Parade C.S.I Malayalam Pastorate. The aims and objectives of SCF are the spiritual, mental and social development of the elderly people in the church and also to help them to involve in all church activities meaningfully. SCF also helps the church to function on sound Christian principles and for the spiritual welfare of the church members.</string>
    <string name="tv121">A group of around 300 children in number who meet every Sunday (except 3rd) at 10:45am. These young minds leave church during service just before the sermon to make it in time for worship which happens in the parish hall. Sunday school begins with a time of worship and then the children head to their class. The vision of Sunday school is that all the children may grow up in the knowledge and love of God, fearing Him and to accept Jesus as their personal Saviour.</string>
    <string name="bt21">Contact Us</string>
    <string name="tv28">We’re so glad you’ve decided to visit us! You’ll find a list of commonly asked questions.</string>
    <string name="tv30">Please don’t hesitate to give us a call at any of our numbers</string>
    <string name="tv61">Annual food sale in July and Wine and Cake sales for Christmas.</string>
    <string name="tv76">Mission field visits, Educational assistance, Monetary support for charities.</string>
    <string name="tv75">Every 3rd Saturday the Women’s Fellowship organizes visits to the sick and needy .</string>
    <string name="tv74">Regular Cottage prayers conducted every 2nd and 3rd Thursday at 3:00pm</string>
    <string name="tv77">Food Sales</string>
    <string name="tv80">Mission Support</string>
    <string name="tv79">Sick Visits</string>
    <string name="tv78">Cottage Prayers</string>
    <string name="b30">Calendar</string>
    <string name="b22">InReach Programs</string>
    <string name="b24">Outreach Programs</string>
    <string name="b23">Youth Meetings</string>
    <string name="tv54">-Build meaningful relationships and involvement with the other organs of the church, such as Sunday School, SCF, Women’s Fellowship, Choir, Family Ministry, etc.</string>
    <string name="tv58">-Grow in a personal relationship with Jesus</string>
    <string name="tv59">-Build healthy and wholesome relations among the youth of the Church</string>
    <string name="tv60">–Participate in the activities such as youth meetings, annual camps, etc.  </string>
    <string name="tv57">The vision of EMY is to help each member to:</string>
    <string name="tv56">The Youth Fellowship of CSI East Parade Malayalam Pastorate, popularly known as EMY, is an assembly of young people of the church in the age group of 14 to 35 years, working together for the glory of God and His most precious name.</string>
    <string name="tv68">There are many members of the church who are bed-ridden and unable to attend the regular church worship service as well as other activities of the church.</string>
    <string name="tv87">Through the in-reach programs, we reach out to these people, go to their home and spend time with them.</string>
    <string name="tv89">We sing songs and also conduct a small worship service at their home. As part of the In-Reach program, we also conduct carol rounds at the homes of the elderly.</string>
    <string name="tv66">We meet every Sunday Morning at 9 AM at the church. These meetings are a time of praise and worship followed by a message by an internal or external speaker. The gists of the messages are posted on the EMY whatsapp brodcast messages.</string>
    <string name="tv70">We have outreach programs once or twice each month. We visit orphanages, hospitals, old age homes, etc. as part of our outreach mission and try to spread a little bit of joy and cheer amongst the people who are normally deprived of the same.</string>
    <string name="tv85">These visits serve as a reminder to us of God’s manifold blessings that have been unconditionally showered on us, which we most often take for granted.</string>
    <string name="tv86">We sing songs and share some snacks with these people and spend some time with them trying to understand them.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_visitus">Map</string>
    <string name="chisttv">
        East Parade Malayalam Pastorate is so closely associated with the Church where it is located now, that it has taken its very name from the Church. But it was neither known by that name in the beginning, nor was it associated with that Church in the first twelve years of its existence. It started as CSI Malayalam Congregation, Bangalore and had varied locations in the city, for worship services in its early years. Its humble beginning is marked by the worship service held for the first time in Malayalam in this city according to the CSI order of service, with just 14 worshippers lead by Rev. V.T.Kurian. That worship service took place not in any Church but in Haigh Memorial hall situated behind the present day Unity Buildings.
        \n\nApart from the Haigh Memorial Hall, the congregation had utilized the Hudson Church also for their services in the beginning. It was however the St. Marks Cathedral that opened its doors for the Malayalam services on a regular basis for the first time in the city.
        \n\nThe arrangement with St. Marks Cathedral had several conditions attached to it such as:
        \n\nThe entire offertory received during the worship services were to be handed over to the Cathedral.
        \nOnly Episcopally ordained ministers were to conduct Holy Communion Services in the Cathedral.
        \nThe Congregation obtained the recognition of the local Diocese viz The Mysore Diocese of CSI on the 29 th of Oct, 1953.
        \nThe congregation also obtained the services of a pastor (Rev. M.K.George) from Madhya Kerala Diocese.
        \nTill then it was Rev. V.T. Kurian who was ministering to the needs of the Congregation in addition to his own duties as a faculty member of the UTC. The arrangement with the St. Marks Cathedral was totally inadequate for a growing congregation.
        \nBy 1957 the total Strength including children had reached 250. Hence the Congregation was exploring other possibilities for conducting their services. It was at that time that Dr.D.R.Sedlo Presbyter of St. Andrew’s Kirk on Cubbon Road came to the aid of Malayalam Congregation.
        \nPermission was granted to use all facilities at St. Andrew’s Kirk for the Worship Services and all other activities of the Malayalam congregation. The congregation moved to the St. Andrew’s Kirk in July 1958. Search for a permanent home St. Andrew’s Kirk however did not prove to be a permanent home for the Malayalam Congregation. They were once again on the look out for a permanent place that they could call their home. During the tenure of Rev. P.O.Varghese, while they were still worshipping at St. Andrew’s, a delegation of congregation members consisting of M/s H.E.Philips, T.C.Chacko, George Cheriyan, P.N.Ninan, C. Chandy (member and City 2 Commissioner of Police) and Miss. Sosamma John met Bishop N.C. Sargant, the Diocesan Bishop and presented their case for allocating a convenient Church for the use of Malayalam Congregation.
        \nThey were successful in their effort as the Bishop could immediately identify East Parade Church for the purpose as it was a Military Church under his charge. They could also obtain a promise from the Bishop to allot the church to the Malayalam Congregation.
        \nThe Malayalam Congregation could however move to the East parade Church only after complete repainting and extensive repairs were carried out to the Church furniture. This was due to the fact, that though the church was a stately building with 95 years of history behind it, it had fallen to bad days after British soldiers had withdrawn from Bangalore cantonment consequent to the granting of Independence to India in 1947.
        \nMalayalam Congregation had to incur considerable expenditure in this effort, exhausting all their reserves of over a decade of existence. Finally they had their first service in East Parade Church on 3rd September 1961. This was a combined service of both Tamil and Malayalam congregations as suggested by Bishop Sargent.
        \n\nA brief word on East Parade Church would appear relevant here. East Parade Church derives its name from its location on the East side of the extensive Parade ground which in those days covered the entire area from Cubbon Park to the present day Dickenson Road. It will be interesting to note that the prestigious Mahatma Gandhi Road was known as ‘The South Parade’ in the pre Independence period, indicating the primacy the Parade ground had during the British regime. The Church was built by Wesleyan Methodist missionaries for the use of British soldiers stationed in Bangalore Cantonment, following Wesleyan traditions of worship. The Church was built in 1865 and was the earliest Church built by them in the Mysore District. A clear inscription on one of the built up stones of the church shows a date 6 th – Oct -1863 which is presumably the date the foundation was laid. One of the annual reports of the Wesleyan mission (1903) reports as under about the East Parade Church:- “The lofty, roomy building is capable of accommodating 700 people. It is looked upon as the Cathedral of Methodism in the Province.” The Church building has a number of unique features. The massive Corinthian columns, all eight in number, stand as sentinels at the entrance of the Church. These columns lend the whole structure its character. Another welcome feature of the building is that unlike other large Churches in Bangalore it has no columns or pillars inside the Church, obstructing the view of the altar. The East parade Church continues to serve two large pastorates viz East parade Tamil and East Parade Malayalam, of the Karnataka Central Diocese of CSI to this day. Members of the two pastorates are ever grateful to the Lord Almighty for His wonderful provisions in preserving and reserving this wonderful Church for their use. The two pastorates had together carried out extensive.renovation to the Church recently and rededicated it for Devine Services on 26-2-2006. There are many more things the two 3 Pastorates can together do in East Parade for the glory of God. Let us pray and hope that God will continue to bestow on the two Pastorates necessary wisdom for this Purpose.
        \n\nAfter adopting East Parade Church as our home, the congregation has made steady steps on the way of progress.
        \nImmediately after entering the East Parade Church the Centenary of the Church was becoming due. Along with the Tamil congregation we participated fully in these celebrations.
        \nAfter the congregation found its home base the immediate priority was to find a home for the pastor. Fortunately the East Parade compound had sufficient space to construct a parsonage of moderate size. Permission was soon obtained from the concerned authorities for the construction. On 6th Oct 1967, the foundation for the Parsonage was laid by Bishop Sargant. Once the foundation was laid, the congregation went full steam ahead and completed the construction in good time. The parsonage was dedicated by Rev.V.T.Kurian on 7th April 1968. .Rev. P.M.Koshy was the first Presbyter who moved into the newly built parsonage. The Parsonage was built with the resources generated by the Malayalam Congregation. More than a decade after the dedication of the Parsonage the Diocese took a decision to build the first floor to our parsonage for the use of the Tamil Pastorate. Simultaneously a little expansion to our own parsonage was also carried out, adding the front verandah and the office room.
        \nThe 125th anniversary of the Church was celebrated jointly by the two congregations under the leadership of Rev. Vincent Rajkumar, Presbyter Tamil Pastorate and Rev. P. U. Paulose, Presbyter Malayalam Pastorate in the year 1990.
        \n\nThe formation of EMPACS (Eastparade Malayalam PAstorate Charitable Society) as a serving arm of the Pastorate in 1992 is one of the most significant steps taken by the Pastorate during its entire history. This step marks the transformation of the Pastorate from merely being a Worshiping community into a Caring community. It also means the pastorate has found its mission in a more meaningful way treating the second part of the Great Commandment given by our Lord Jesus Christ in his summary of the law and the prophets as equal to the first .God wanted both these parts to be given equal importance. When God decides to do something he first provides the persons for that purpose. Rev.Thomas K Oommen was the man chosen by God to form EMPACS as part of the Malayalam Pastorate .He was also provided with a young and enthusiastic Pastorate Secretary viz.Mr George Varghese just for a one year term(1992-93).The two of them together could find sufficient members in the Pastorate who shared their enthusiasm for doing something for the vulnerable sections of our society .The bye-laws and the Constitution were soon drawn up and approved by the promoters. The Secretary lost no time in getting the Society registered by the Registrar of Societies, Government of Karnataka. He also managed to get the Society registered with the Income Tax authorities under clauses12A and 80Gof the Income Tax Act. The first six months of the Society found phenomenal progress in its activities .A convenient compound was identified with the required built in accommodation in Anthony Layout in Lingarajpuram which was leased out in favour of the Society. The space available on the property was adequate for running an old age home and a Centre for Brain Injured Children. The Centre for Brain Injured Children was a boon for many such children in the near-by slum environment, who were left to their fate, often tied to a cot or a pillar when their parents went out to earn a living. Over the years the Society has been able to procure land from the BDA and build its own accommodation for the School for Brain Injured Children named ASHRAYA. They have also built up another school for normal children with special emphasis on economically backward children, in the Byppanahalli area. The Society is now looking to expand their activities .
        \n\nRev. Christopher Kurien had a very short tenure of just one year as Presbyter in charge of the Pastorate (1997-98). But during that one year he was able to take several initiatives for the benefit of the Pastorate. Failure to mention them will amount to ingratitude .Three of these initiatives are mentioned below:-
        \n( i .) For the first time in its history a regular office for the Pastorate was established with dedicated staff for that purpose.
        \n(ii.) Senior Christian Fellowship to cater to the spiritual and mental needs of the older members of the church (above 60 years) was started.
        \n(iii.) Golden Jubilee Celebrations of this Pastorate was launched although bulk of the year long celebrations took place under the over view of Rev.L E Sahanam.
        \n\nThe formation of the Malayalam Congregation as already mentioned took place in 1949.It was therefore decided to have an year long golden jubilee celebrations during 1998-99.A special committee was formed for this purpose under the chairmanship of the presbyter in charge. All the organs of the pastorate were actively involved in the celebrations. Some of the salient events that took place as part of the celebrations are mentioned below:- 1. The celebrations were launched in a public meeting held in our church at 2 pm on palm Sunday 1998.The participants included Rev. Victor Joshua, Diocesan Secretary, Rev Dr M J Joseph, Director ECC, Rev M P Yohannan, Vicar Primrose Church and Rev Abraham Marat, Vicar of Orthodox Church Hosur Road .During the meeting the surviving founding members of the Congregation namely Mr. T C Chacko, Mrs Sosamma John and Mr. C John Varghese were honoured. 2. A Workshop was held for the members of the Pastorate (85 members attended) between 12th and 14th of June 1998 at St Marks Parish Hall with Mr. Paul Siromony and Dr Daniel Chetty of the senate of Serampur University as facilitators. The workshop among other things could formulate a mission statement for the Pastorate and draw up an action plan for the future. 3. The Golden Jubilee Committee invited Justice V R Krishna Iyer to address the Pastorate giving an external view on the mission of the church. Justice Krishna Iyer commenced his address stating that what he was going to present was not an external view as he considered himself as an insider .He lauded the good work done by Christian Institutions and emphasized the fact that,” Such good works were possible not because people happened to be good but because they were motivated by a spiritual power to serve the needy with immense zeal and in a spirit of sacrifice.” 4. Another event that attracted a lot of attention during the Golden Jubilee was the Gana Mela by K J Jesudas and party held on 22/8/98 at the St Joseph’s playground.Mr M K Oommen was the person mostly responsible for this event. 5. The annual spiritual Convention of the Pastorate was conducted in an enhanced way with six days of convention led by Rev.Valsan Thampu of St Stephen’s College, Delhi. 6. The Senior Christian Fellowship of the church organized a one day seminar at the church with the youth fellowship on family relationships to which several prominent speakers were invited. 7. The final valedictory meeting of the Golden Jubilee year was held in our church on April 1999 with a large gathering including a number of former presbyters in charge .The chief guests included Justice Saldhana, Mr. Philipose Mathai, Secretary Government of Karnataka, Mr P S.S Thomas .Secretary Government of Karnataka and Rt. Rev. Vasanth Kumar the Diocesan Bishop. The Golden Jubilee committee consisted of the following persons:- Rev. L.E.Sahanam Chairman K.P.Luke Vydhian General Convenor O.Mathai Treasurer Rev. Dr. George Oommen Convenor Souvenir P.N.Abraham Convenor Events 6 Samuel Johnson Convenor Projects Moncy John Convenor Outreach And John Idicula Convenor Fund Raising The little sapling that sprouted on Palm Sunday 1949 has grown in all sense of the word in the last sixty years with as many as four congregations flourishing in different parts of the city today as off-shoots of the mother plant, which by itself is over 500 families strong. But growth is not only to be measured by numbers and size alone but also by the values it promotes in the environs it is placed .Sixtieth Anniversary of the Pastorate is therefore an occasion for introspection and self-evaluation. We should ask ourselves how far we have been true to the Mission statement adopted by us during the Workshop held in June 1998.All that has been achieved so far are due to the sheer Grace of God. We can not claim any credit or merit for ourselves. Let us rededicate ourselves whole heartedly to carry out the mission assigned to us by the Lord.
        \n\nPresently, the Church has over 2250 members and nearly 800 families.
    </string>
</resources>
